Guide to the Henry Jasik Papers RG.029
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Henry Jasik Papers
1948-1987
1958-1968
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Jasik, Henry
RG.029
31
1.5 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Henry Jasik (1919-1977) was a prominent scientist in the field of antenna engineering. After completing his doctoral studies in Electrical Engineering at the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn in 1953, he went on to found his own company, Jasik Laboratories, Inc. Jasik maintained his ties to Polytechnic, working closely with the Microwave Research Institute throughout his career. His Antenna Engineering Handbook, first published in 1961, is still widely referenced today.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Jasik (1919-1977) received a BS in Electrical Engineering from Newark College of Engineering in 1938, a Master of Electrical Engineering from Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn in 1951 and a Doctor of Electrical Engineering from Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn in 1953.
After he graduated from Newark College of Engineering, Jasik worked for the Navy and the Civil Aeronautics Administration, assisting with radio aids to air navigation and airborne radar and communications antennas. After some time as an independent consultant and completing his graduate work at the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, Jasik founded Jasik Laboratories, Inc. in 1955. His company focused on the design, manufacture, and testing of various antenna types. Jasik was elected a Fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers in 1958 for his contributions to "the theory and design of VHP and microwave antennas." Jasik's Antenna Engineering Handbook was first published in 1961 and is still wildly referenced today.
Source: "Dedication." Antenna Engineering Handbook: Third Edition, Richard Johnson, ed., McGraw-Hill, New York, 1993.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains binders, albums, and notebooks relating to Jasik's antenna research. These items contain a variety of material types, including published articles (by Jasik and colleagues), lab reports, photographs, notes, and correspondence.
The collection also contains biographical information about Jasik, his connection to Polytechnic's Microwave Research Institute, and memoranda detailing the donation of Jasik's library to the Polytechnic Institute of New York.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by format type and subject into two series:
Series I: Loose notes and reports
Series II: Albums and binders
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Photographs; Electrical engineering; Articles; Laboratory report; Antennas (electronics)
- Series I: Notes and Reports, 1949-1987; 10926
  - Jasik Library donation to Polytechnic Institute of New York, 1982, 1987; cuid2444; 10927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Antenna Engineering Handbook outline, notes, and correspondence, 1954-1961; cuid2445; 10928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Henry Jasik Papers notebook (contains articles, correspondence, and proposals), 1948-1968; cuid2446; 10929 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Henry Jasik Fundamentals of Antennas notebook, circa 1965; cuid2447; 10930 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Jasik Laboratories Progress Report notebook, 1960; cuid2448; 10931 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Jasik Laboratories Technical Proposal notebook, 1965; cuid2449; 10932 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Antenna, Antenna Systems, Engineering & Analysis notebook, circa 1967; cuid2450; 10933 (Box 1, Item 5)
  - General Theory of Communication, by Arthur E. Lammel (Microwave Research Institute), 1949; cuid2451; 10934 (Box 1, Item 6)
- Series II: Albums and Binders, 10935
  - Henry Jasik Paper on X-Ray binder (articles and notes), 1934-1986; 1964-1978; cuid2452; 10936 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Henry Jasik Paper on X-Ray binder (articles and notes), 1971-1986; cuid2453; 10937 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Henry Jasik Publicity album (clippings, photographs, product advertisements), 1955-1964; cuid2454; 10938 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Antennas for Radio Astronomy Research album (photographs, articles), 1958-1987; cuid2455; 10939 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - Miscellaneous Antennas and Associated Components album (photographs), circa 1960s; cuid2456; 10940 (Box 2, Item 5)